Growing a personal brand is difficult,
it's hard, it takes a lot of time.
You're going to have to become a content
creator, a director, an editor, a
storyteller.
There's so many different things, and
when you get good at those, you
become the personal brand,
and the personal brand
is pretty much the person that
goes front and center of the business to
win business.
It's not always easy to do,
and I think that sometimes we can muddy
the process a
little bit. The idea is
that you need seven hours in front of
someone
before they consider buying your shit,
pretty much.
Now, this was from a Google study,
I think ages ago, and I'm pretty
sure Daniel Priestley in his book
"Oversubscribed" said,
"Seven hours of you,
11 touch points,
four pieces of content across four
modalities." And the
idea here is, let's just imagine
that that's true,
that you need seven hours.
And I look back to it,
and I told you about that time that I
was really desperate,
and I just went live.
And the reason I went live wasn't building
a personal brand.
It wasn't to get seven hours.
I went live because I didn't know how to
edit.
I didn't have a camera.
I didn't know how to chop up pieces of
content and put it
out. So I was like,
I'm just going to get my phone.
I'm going to put it on a tripod.
Facebook Live. I take a deep breath, go.
Hit live.
And every day I went live because I didn't
know how to make
content any other way. And I
was kind of wondering,
why have I got so many people
doing business with me?
And it's because people were sat
and watching me for half
an hour every single day, like a TV show.
I started working with my manager because
he messaged me and went, "Mate, if you
can hold people for half an hour on a live
stream, you could do live events."
He was like, "This is a no-brainer." So
if I was doing half an hour a day, that
means within two weeks of people watching
my lives, they'd hit that seven hours.
So if we just imagine that this is a rule,
and for some people, it could be 10
hours, some people it might be three.
But rather than getting really caught up
in the intricacies of content creation,
short-form hooks, setups, payoffs,
algorithms, TikTok, TikTok short,
all of this
stuff. Imagine if we were just saying,
"Yo,
we need to get seven hours in front of
people." So if we say the average
Instagram video is a minute
long, that's considering
that they watch the entire minute, which
for most people is no,
they're just not going to.
But let's say it is.
So if you wanted to get
that seven hours in front of someone,
posting
three times a week is two
and a half years.
Posting five times a week
is still 1.6 years. That's a long time.
And no offense, but if I said to you guys,
"Hey, if you post on Instagram, you'll
have an online business soon." "Oh, yeah?
How soon?" "Yeah, two,
three years." You're like, "Oh,
it's not really that sexy."
So if we're going to use short-form
content as a means of getting...
And I'm not shitting on short-form
content.
Bought my house, set up my life,
sold out Hammersmith Apollo,
sold out the City
Upper House. Don't get me wrong,
it did a lot for me.
But trying to build a personal brand with
very short pieces of
content, I think, is not the meta play.
Because I'll be honest,
when I look at some of the other people in
the lineup, I
can actually see behind their eyes some
people are getting a little bit short with
the process of creating short-form
content. It's a daily grind.
It's turning up daily.
You're having to compete with a lot of
low-quality content
creators. Before TikTok, it
was people that had a camera,
that knew how to edit,
that were putting out content.
But then when TikTok came along
and CapCut and the
app,
actually any fucking idiot can create
short-form content.
So suddenly so many people are fighting,
and you've got AI, you've got scripting,
you've got all of these hooks.
When I look, for instance, in jujitsu,
if I'm
against someone bigger than me,
or they're stronger than me,
I'm going to think, "What
is this person's weakness?
I'm going to fight them there." I'm not
going to go fight them where their
strengths are. So
when I look at short-form content,
I'm like, "That looks pretty
competitive.
I might just fuck off to a space where
they're all shit." And YouTube
is a good space for that. So one minute,
two and a half years.
Let's go look at YouTube for a second.
And again, same rules apply.
Because if you say
that the average YouTube video used to be
13 minutes, it's now
11 minutes because you ADHD fucks,
no doubt.
But there's just some raw maths here.
So that means that if people
are watching my videos for 11 minutes,
and I posted
three times a week,
in a quarter of a year, in three months,
in three
months, we could suddenly have
that person accruing seven hours.
Again, of course, that means
that they're going to have to watch quite
a
considerable amount of that.
So I'm not saying here that YouTube
is better
than short-form. I'm just saying,
when you're going to protect the longevity
of
your career, and for the next five years,
you young fucks are going to be fine
posting out content every day.
But I kind of burned out twice in my
career, and I'm
now at a point where putting out two
videos a week and just stepping back is
fucking nice. Don't get me wrong.
You still got to eat shit for a few years,
people. By the way,
you got to eat so much shit,
you forget what it tastes like
to not eat shit. But after that, this
is your exit strategy, right?
So don't jump the gun
and get into fucking YouTube. All right,
mate?
Eat your shit, enjoy it, bomb, burn out,
go dead behind the eyes like
Adam Sullivan in his most recent reels.
Then after that, come to YouTube.